{
  "questions": [
    {
      "index": 1,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "Which is the driest place on the North American continent?",
      "options": ["Death Valley", "Sonoran Desert", "Mojave Desert", "Great Basin Desert"],
      "answer": "Death Valley",
      "hint": "The place is also the lowest and hottest place in North America."
    },
    {
      "index": 2,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "What is the name of the longest mountain range of North America?",
      "options": ["Andes Mountains", "Appalachian Mountains", "Rocky Mountains", "Canadian Shield"],
      "answer": "Rocky Mountains",
      "hint": "The range stretches some 3000 miles across Canada, United States, and Mexico."
    },
    {
      "index": 3,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "Which ocean borders North America in the east?",
      "options": ["Atlantic Ocean", "Gulf of Mexico", "Pacific Ocean", "Antarctic Ocean"],
      "answer": "Atlantic Ocean",
      "hint": "The ocean separates North America and Europe."
    },
    {
      "index": 4,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "What is the highest point in North America?",
      "options": ["Mount Hayes", "Mount Logan", "Mount Helen", "Mount McKinley"],
      "answer": "Mount McKinley",
      "hint": "The peak is located in Alaska, United States."
    },
    {
      "index": 5,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "Which is the largest lake in North America?",
      "options": ["Lake Michigan", "Lake Ontario", "Lake Superior", "Great Salt Lake"],
      "answer": "Lake Superior",
      "hint": "The lake is the largest freshwater lake in the world by surface area and the third largest by volume."
    },
    {
      "index": 6,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "Which is the national animal of the USA?",
      "options": ["Moose", "American Bison", "Reindeer", "Polar Bear"],
      "answer": "American Bison",
      "hint": "The animal is commonly called 'buffalo,' but they’re actually not buffalo!"
    },
    {
      "index": 7,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "What is the collective name for the string of islands at the southern tip of Florida?",
      "options": ["Caribbean Islands", "Aleutian Islands", "Florida Keys", "Greater Antilles"],
      "answer": "Florida Keys",
      "hint": "The islands are situated off the southern tip of Florida and surrounded by the Gulf of Mexico to the north and the Atlantic Ocean to the south."
    },
    {
      "index": 8,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "In which U.S. state is the Everglades National Park?",
      "options": ["Hawaii", "Florida", "Oregon", "California"],
      "answer": "Florida",
      "hint": "Everglades is one of the world’s largest tropical wetlands and has the Gulf of Mexico on its southern end."
    },
    {
      "index": 9,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "True or false? Grizzly bears are fast runners.",
      "options": ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
      "answer": "TRUE",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 10,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "Which animal would you expect to see in the grassland biome?",
      "options": ["American Bison", "Elk", "Moose", "Lynx"],
      "answer": "American Bison",
      "hint": "These are formidable beasts and the heaviest land animals in North America."
    },
    {
      "index": 11,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "What is the national bird of the United States?",
      "options": ["Peregrine Falcon", "Bald Eagle", "Wild Turkey", "Great Horned Owl"],
      "answer": "Bald Eagle",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 12,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "Which of these bear species is unique to North America?",
      "options": ["Polar Bears", "Sun Bears", "Sloth Bears", "Grizzly Bears"],
      "answer": "Grizzly Bears",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 13,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "The American pika is a small mammal that lives where?",
      "options": ["Lake Superior", "Rocky Mountains", "Appalachian Mountains", "Great Salt Lake"],
      "answer": "Rocky Mountains",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 14,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "Which river flows through the Grand Canyon?",
      "options": ["Colorado River", "Columbia River", "Mississippi River", "Rio Grande"],
      "answer": "Colorado River",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 15,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "This famous waterfall located on the borders of USA and Canada is popularly known as?",
      "options": ["Victoria Falls", "Niagara Falls", "Yosemite Falls", "Multnomah Falls"],
      "answer": "Niagara Falls",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 16,
      "category": "The Land",
      "question": "The geographical feature is a broad region of Precambrian rock that encircles Hudson Bay. What is this feature known as?",
      "options": ["Rocky Mountains", "Great Plains", "Canadian Shield", "Appalachian Mountains"],
      "answer": "Canadian Shield",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 17,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "On which day do U.S. Americans celebrate Independence Day?",
      "options": ["4th of July", "15th of August", "20th of February", "25th of December"],
      "answer": "4th of July",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 18,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "How many stars appear on the flag of the United States?",
      "options": ["52", "48", "50", "46"],
      "answer": "50",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 19,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "The ruins of the ancient Mayan city of Palenque are found in which country?",
      "options": ["Mexico", "Belize", "Guatemala", "Panama"],
      "answer": "Mexico",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 20,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "The best-preserved mummies in North America can be viewed in which city?",
      "options": ["Ottawa, Canada", "Nuuk, Greenland", "New York City, United States", "Vancouver, Canada"],
      "answer": "Nuuk, Greenland",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 21,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "Although a part of North America, Greenland is a territory of which country?",
      "options": ["Iceland", "United States of America", "Denmark", "United Kingdom"],
      "answer": "Denmark",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 22,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "In which city would you find the Statue of Liberty?",
      "options": ["Philadelphia", "New York City", "Washington D.C.", "San Francisco"],
      "answer": "New York City",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 23,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "Which is the largest city in North America?",
      "options": ["New York City", "Toronto", "Mexico City", "San Francisco"],
      "answer": "Mexico City",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 24,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "How many countries are there in Central America?",
      "options": ["6", "7", "8", "9"],
      "answer": "7",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 25,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "Which language is the most commonly spoken in Central America?",
      "options": ["Creole", "Portuguese", "Spanish", "Miskito"],
      "answer": "Spanish",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 26,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "The waterway in Panama that connects the Atlantic Ocean with the Pacific Ocean is known as:",
      "options": ["Champlain Canal", "Florida Canal", "Panama Canal", "Orleans Canal"],
      "answer": "Panama Canal",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 27,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "Which Native American people lived in the Arctic region?",
      "options": ["Aztec", "Inca", "Maya", "Inuit"],
      "answer": "Inuit",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 28,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "The ancient culture of the Maya developed in what is now the present-day region of which three countries?",
      "options": ["USA, Canada, Greenland", "Mexico, Belize, Guatemala", "Mexico, Panama, Nicaragua", "USA, Mexico, Guatemala"],
      "answer": "Mexico, Belize, Guatemala",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 29,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "Which Native American civilization built the city of Machu Picchu?",
      "options": ["Aztec", "Inca", "Maya", "Olmec"],
      "answer": "Inca",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 30,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "Which Native American civilization built the ancient city of Tenochtitlán?",
      "options": ["Inca", "Olmec", "Aztec", "Maya"],
      "answer": "Aztec",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 31,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "This Native American civilization was known for creating a calendar and pyramids. Who were they?",
      "options": ["Inca", "Olmec", "Aztec", "Maya"],
      "answer": "Maya",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 32,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "Which U.S. state was originally called the Sandwich Islands?",
      "options": ["Hawaii", "Alaska", "California", "Washington"],
      "answer": "Hawaii",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 33,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "Which country is known as the Land of the Rising Sun?",
      "options": ["China", "India", "Japan", "South Korea"],
      "answer": "Japan",
      "hint": ""
    },
    {
      "index": 34,
      "category": "The People",
      "question": "Which country is famous for inventing pasta and pizza?",
      "options": ["France", "Italy", "Greece", "Mexico"],
      "answer": "Italy",
      "hint": ""
    }
  ]
}
